{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The wet bulb temperature during sensible heating of air", "opta": "remains constant", "optb": "increases", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The C.O.P. of an absorption type refrigerator is given by (where T1 = Temperature at which the working substance receives heat, T2 = Temperature of cooling water, and T3 = Evaporator temperature)", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is wrong?", "opta": "The heat transfer in liquid and gases takes place according to convection.", "optb": "The amount of heat flow through a body is dependent upon the material of the body.", "optc": "The thermal conductivity of solid metals increases with rise in temperature,", "optd": "Logarithmic mean temperature difference is not equal to the arithmetic mean temperature difference.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In free convection heat transfer transition from laminar to turbulent flow is governed by the critical value of the", "opta": "Reynold's number", "optb": "Grashoff's number", "optc": "Reynold's number, Grashoff's number", "optd": "Prandtl number, Grashoff's number", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a refrigerating machine, heat rejected is __________ heat absorbed.", "opta": "equal to", "optb": "less than", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The humidity ratio or specific humidity is the mass of water vapour present in", "opta": "1 m3 of wet air", "optb": "1 m3 of dry air", "optc": "1 kg of wet air", "optd": "1 kg of dry air", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The formation of frost on cooling coils in a refrigerator", "opta": "increases heat transfer", "optb": "improves C.O.P. of the system", "optc": "increases power consumption", "optd": "reduces power consumption", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The by-pass factor for a cooling coil", "opta": "increases with increase in velocity of air passing through it", "optb": "decreases with increase in velocity of air passing through it", "optc": "remains unchanged with increase in velocity of air passing through it", "optd": "may increase or decrease with increase in velocity of air passing through it depending upon the condition of air entering", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The difference between dry bulb temperature and wet bulb temperature, is called", "opta": "dry bulb depression", "optb": "wet bulb depression", "optc": "dew point depression", "optd": "degree of saturation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Defrosting of a refrigerator may be done by stopping the compressor for a short period.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "According to Dalton's law of partial pressures, (where pb = Barometric pressure, pa = Partial pressure of dry air, and pv = Partial pressure of water vapour)", "opta": "Pb = pa - pv", "optb": "Pb = pa + pv", "optc": "Pb = pa x pv", "optd": "Pb = pa/pv", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The heat transfer by conduction through a thick sphere is given by", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The relative humidity is defined as", "opta": "the mass of water vapour present in 1 m3 of dry air", "optb": "the mass of water vapour present in 1 kg of dry air", "optc": "the ratio of the actual mass of water vapour in a unit mass of dry air to the mass of water vapour in the same mass of dry air when it is saturated at the same temperature and pressure.", "optd": "the ratio of actual mass of water vapour in a given volume of moist air to the mass of water vapour in the same volume of saturated air at the same temperature and pressure", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fourier's law of heat conduction is (where Q = Amount of heat flow through the body in unit time, A = Surface area of heat flow, taken at right angles to the direction of heat flow, dT = Temperature difference on the two faces of the body, dx = Thickness of the body, through which the heat flows, taken along the direction of heat flow, and k = Thermal conductivity of the body)", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The heat transfer by conduction through a thick sphere is same as through a thick cylinder.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In aqua-ammonia and Lithium-bromide water absorption refrigeration systems, the refrigerants are respectively", "opta": "water and water", "optb": "water and lithium bromide", "optc": "ammonia and lithium bromide", "optd": "ammonia and water", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As relative humidity decreases, the dew point temperature will be __________ wet bulb temperature.", "opta": "same as", "optb": "lower than", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The process of heat transfer from a hot body to a cold body, in a straight line, without affecting the intervening medium, is called radiation.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Reynolds number (RN) is given by (where h = Film coefficient, l = Linear dimension, V = Velocity of fluid, k = Thermal conductivity, t = Temperature, \u03c1 = Density of fluid, cp = Specific heat at constant pressure, and \u03bc = Coefficient of absolute viscosity)", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The optimum effective temperature for human comfort is", "opta": "higher in winter than in summer", "optb": "lower in winter than in summer", "optc": "same in winter and summer", "optd": "not dependent on season", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The wet bulb temperature lines, on the psychrometric chart, are curved lines.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The sensible heat factor during cooling and dehumidification process is given by (where h1 = Enthalpy of air entering the cooling coil, h2 = Enthalpy of air leaving the cooling coil, and hA = Enthalpy of air at the end of dehumidification process)", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Thermal diffusivity is a", "opta": "function of temperature", "optb": "physical property of a substance", "optc": "dimensionless parameter", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The condition of refrigerant after leaving the compressor and before entering the condenser is superheated vapour.", "opta": "Yes", "optb": "No", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The total radiation from a black body per second per unit area is __________ fourth power of the absolute temperature. This statement is known as Stefan-Boltzmann law.", "opta": "equal to", "optb": "directly proportional to", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following represents a heat pump?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a psychrometric process, the sensible heat added is 30 kJ/s and the latent heat added is 20 kJ/s. The sensible heat factor for the process will be", "opta": "0.3", "optb": "0.6", "optc": "0.67", "optd": "1.5", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The amount of radiation mainly depends upon the", "opta": "nature of the body", "optb": "temperature of the body", "optc": "type of surface of the body", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For ammonia refrigerating systems, the tubes of a shell and tube condenser are made of", "opta": "copper", "optb": "aluminium", "optc": "steel", "optd": "brass", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The highest thermal diffusivity is of", "opta": "iron", "optb": "lead", "optc": "concrete", "optd": "wood", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "While designing the refrigeration system of an aircraft, the prime consideration is that the", "opta": "system has high C.O.P.", "optb": "power per TR is low", "optc": "mass of refrigerant circulated in the system is low", "optd": "mass of the refrigeration equipment is low", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The heat transfer takes place according to", "opta": "Zeroth law of thermodynamics", "optb": "First law of thermodynamics", "optc": "Second law of thermodynamics", "optd": "Kirchhoff's law", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An electrolux refrigerator is called a __________ absorption system.", "opta": "single fluid", "optb": "two fluids", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The heat transfer by radiation __________ a medium.", "opta": "requires", "optb": "does not require", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Thermal conductivity of water __________ with rise in temperature.", "opta": "remains same", "optb": "decreases", "optc": "increases", "optd": "may increase or decrease depending upon temperature", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During adiabatic saturation process on unsaturated air __________ remains constant.", "opta": "relative humidity", "optb": "dew point temperature", "optc": "dry bulb temperature", "optd": "wet bulb temperature", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The thickness of thermal and hydrodynamic boundary layer is equal if Prandtl number is", "opta": "equal to one", "optb": "greater than one", "optc": "less than one", "optd": "equal to Nusselt number", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A perfect black body is one which", "opta": "is black in colour", "optb": "absorbs heat radiations of all wave lengths falling on it", "optc": "reflects all the heat radiations", "optd": "transmits the heat radiations", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Degree of saturation or percentage humidity is", "opta": "the mass of water vapour present in 1 m3 of dry air", "optb": "the mass of water vapour present in 1 kg of dry air", "optc": "the ratio of the actual mass of water vapour in a unit mass of dry air to the mass of water vapour in the same mass of dry air when it is saturated at the same temperature and pressure.", "optd": "the ratio of actual mass of water vapour in a given volume of moist air to the mass of water vapour in the same volume of saturated air at the same temperature and pressure", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The coefficient of performance of Heat Pump is always __________ one.", "opta": "equal to", "optb": "less than", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During a refrigeration cycle, heat is rejected by the refrigerant in a", "opta": "compressor", "optb": "condenser", "optc": "evaporator", "optd": "expansion valve", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A refrigeration system", "opta": "removes heat from a low temperature body and delivers it to a high temperature body", "optb": "removes heat from a high temperature body and delivers it to a low temperature body", "optc": "rejects energy to a low temperature body", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The subcooling in a refrigeration cycle", "opta": "does not alter C.O.P.", "optb": "increases C.O.P.", "optc": "decreases C.O.P.", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Nusselt number (NN) is given by", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During sensible cooling of air __________ decreases.", "opta": "wet bulb temperature", "optb": "relative humidity", "optc": "dry bulb temperature", "optd": "specific humidity", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The critical radius is the insulation radius at which the resistance to heat flow is", "opta": "maximum", "optb": "minimum", "optc": "zero", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In case of solids, the heat transfer takes place according to radiation.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A water cooled condenser operates at a __________ condensing temperature than an air-cooled condenser.", "opta": "higher", "optb": "lower", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The relative humidity decreases as air gets wet.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The temperature of ammonia after compression in a vapour compression system is", "opta": "20 to 50\u00b0 C", "optb": "50 to 70\u00b0 C", "optc": "70 to 110\u00b0 C", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}